Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Audrey Himmelstein Del Grosso papers, 1986-2002 and undated RL.11479
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Audrey Himmelstein Del Grosso papers
1986-2002 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
Del Grosso, Audrey Himmelstein
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11479
2.5 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. Audrey Himmelstein Del Grosso was an advertising executive with JWT Direct, a direct marketing subsidiary of JWT. Includes correspondence, VHS videotapes, optical disks, research reports, direct marketing mailers and brochures, and other printed materials. Companies represented include Bear Stearns, Bell Atlantic (now AT&T), Citibank, Ford, Heinz and IBM. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Account Files; Artifacts; Audiovisual Materials.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. Audrey Himmelstein Del Grosso was an advertising executive with JWT Direct, a direct marketing subsidiary of JWT. Del Grosso: BA, English Literature, SUNY Binghamton; MBA, New York University; Senior Account Executive, Benton & Bowles 1984-1985; Account Supervisor, Senior Vice President, J. Walter Thompson and JWT Direct, 1985-1997; Managing Director, Bear, Stearns, 1997-2000; Marketing Consultant, NYC & Company, 2001-2002; Senior Vice President, JP Morgan Chase 2002-2011
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Audrey Himmelstein Del Grosso papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections: J. Walter Thompson Company Account Files; J. Walter Thompson Company Brouillard Communications vertical files; Ralph Rydholm papers; Wunderman Archives.
Collection Overview
Includes correspondence, VHS videotapes, optical disks, research reports, direct marketing mailers and brochures, and other printed materials. Companies represented include Bear Stearns, Bell Atlantic (now AT&T), Citibank, Ford, Heinz and IBM. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising, Direct marketing -- History; Advertising, Direct-mail -- United States; Advertising executives; Advertising agencies; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Bell Atlantic Corporation; Ford Motor Company; International Business Machines Corporation
- General Files, 1986-2002 and undated; 1
  - 9/11 public relations campaigns (includes NYC & Company), 2001-2002; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and photograph, 1989-1991 (Box 1)
  - J. Walter Thompson Advertising Planning Methods, undated (Box 1)
  - J. Walter Thompson Yearbook, 1986 (Box 1)
- Accounts, 1987-2000 and undated; 2
  - Bear Stearns--Corporate Media Presentation, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Bear Stearns--Creative, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - Bear Stearns--Media Plan, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Bear Stearns--Positioning Research, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Bell Atlantic--Data services mailers, undated (Box 1)
  - Bell Atlantic--Defense Telecommunications Service-Washington (DTS-W), 1992 (Box 1)
  - Bell Atlantic--DRTV Test Results Topline, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Bell Atlantic--Guardian DRTV analysis, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Bell Atlantic--ISDN Product Launch, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Bell Atlantic--Meeting Future Challenges Together, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Bell Atlantic--Print advertisement, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Bell Atlantic--Print advertisements and miscellaneous, 1994-1996 (Box 6)
  - Bell Atlantic--Regional Bell mailers, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Bell Atlantic--Small Business Communications guide, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Bell Atlantic--Thinx mailers, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Bell Atlantic--Thinx kaleidescope mailer, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Bell Atlantic--Video services mailers, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - Citibank--Where Do We Go From Here? presentation, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Ford--Direct Marketing Update for JWT International Offices, circa 1989 (Box 2)
  - Ford--Festiva direct marketing, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Ford--Simulator, 1990-1992 (Box 3)
  - Ford--Simulator, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Ford--Taurus direct marketing, 1989 (Box 3)
  - H.J. Heinz new business presentation, 1996 (Box 3)
  - IBM sales support brochures, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - IBM sales support brochures, 1988 (Box 6)
  - NYC & Company--New York Tourism, 2001-2002 (Box 6)
  - Sprint--Dimes N Destinations advertisement, 1996 (Box 6)
- Artifacts, 1989 and undated; 3
  - J. Walter USA/Miller High Life mug, undated (Box 4)
  - JWT Linden desk clock, undated (Box 4)
  - J. Walter Thompson 125th anniversary medal, 1989 (Box 4)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1990-2001 and undated; 4
  - Wolf Group; NYC & Company: Paint the Town Red White and Blue. Whoopi Says, 2001 (Box 5, Video-cassette RL11479-VHS-001)
  - Wolf Group--NY State Tourism: Whoopi Says, 2001 (Box 5, Video-cassette RL11479-VHS-002)
  - Nancy Richard Group: Come Back to New York Campaign. I Love New York, undated (Box 5, Optical-disc RL11479-OP-001)
  - Wolf Group/Steel Rose--NYC & Company; Paul Says :60, undated (Box 5, Optical-disc RL11479-OP-002)
  - Ford Simulator computer disks, 1990-1992 (Box 5)